Temitope Abisola

+447771053907 | abisolatemitope38@gmail.com

https://maltigold.github.io/Portfolio/ || http://www.linkedin.com/in/temitopeabisola

SUMMARY

A Broadminded Data Scientist/Analyst and Machine Learning Engineer with proficiency working with Python and its ecosystem, R, SQL, and other data tools for data analysis, forecasting, predicting, and visualizing. Experienced in developing and deploying cutting-edge machine learning models and algorithms to drive business growth and optimize decision-making processes and motivated to take on new initiatives as an individual and part of a team, utilizing data science/machine learning skills including algorithm designs and data structures to solve problems.

SKILLS

- Languages: R, Python, SQL, SAS.
- Softwares: Excel, Tableau, PowerBI.
- Platforms: MS Azure, Apache Spark, MySQL, OracleSQL.
- Tools: Tensorflow, statistical modeling, big data, deep learning.
- Experience with cloud platforms such as MS Azure and GCP
- Excellent knowledge of data visualization tools.
- Familiar with the AWS suite of products such as Sage.
- Comfortable learning new applications.

PROJECTS

Portfolio: https://maltigold.github.io/Portfolio/

Machine Learning Engineer Project

Proxy Machine Learning Models for Explainability

Tech-stack: Python, Pandas, Numpy, PyTorch, Seaborn, Sckit-learn, Matplotlib, OverLeaf, Git.

- Conducted extensive research, and created and implemented a machine learning model capable of explaining and providing transparent insights into the decision-making process of complex machine learning models.
- A black-box model (complex machine learning models) was built and then the prediction output of the black-box model to train the proxy models.
- The best-performing proxy model after it was trained with the black-box predictions output was the "Decision Tree Model" which explains 88% of the variance of the black-box predictions.

Data Scientist/Machine Learning Engineer

Car Price Prediction

- In this project, the primary objective was to effectively leverage a database containing anonymized vehicle advertisements and to predict the price of a car given some parameters.
- By Seamlessly integrating data preprocessing, feature engineering, optimal regression model selection, and comprehensive interpretability
 analysis, this project accomplished a nuanced understanding of vehicle price prediction, bolstered by the successful deployment of
 advanced machine learning techniques.

Robotic-Assisted Surgery in Healthcare Prediction of Diabetic Retinopathy from Fundus Photography Images of Patients Using Deep Learning Algorithms.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst - Freelance October 2023 – Present

- Utilize statistical techniques to interpret and analyze data, presenting findings through comprehensive reports.
- Spearheaded the development and execution of databases, data collection systems, and analytics strategies to enhance statistical efficiency and accuracy.
- Identify and dissect trends and patterns within intricate data sets, enabling informed decision-making.
- Employed data cleaning techniques to refine and enhance data quality, resolving code issues to ensure accuracy.
- Collaborate with management to prioritize organizational and informational requirements, aligning efforts with business objectives.
- Source data from primary and secondary channels while ensuring the maintenance and integrity of databases and data systems.
- Proactively identify and define opportunities for process enhancements to drive continuous improvement initiatives.

Data Analyst – Stellar Beverages Ltd

August 2020 – September 2022

- Collected and analyzed data from various sources to identify trends, patterns, and insights related to manufacturing processes and production output.
- Developed and maintained databases, spreadsheets, and other data management systems to organize and store manufacturing data.
- Used data visualization tools, such as graphs and charts, to communicate insights and findings to stakeholders clearly and concisely.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, such as engineering, production, and quality control, to identify areas for improvement and make recommendations for process optimization.
- Developed and implemented data-driven solutions to improve manufacturing efficiency, productivity, and quality.
- Monitored key performance indicators (KPIs) to assess manufacturing processes' success and identify improvement areas.

- Boosted business acquisition with strategic prospecting initiatives and favorable partnerships.
- Served as the primary contact for client service teams for several projects.
- Developed reports to inform operational strategy and decision-making.
- Optimized Investment portfolios to support client objectives and reduced company and client risk through credit application processes and review of approval criteria.
- Reduced company and client risks through credit application processes and approval/denial criteria review.
- Managed and maintained current retail business relationships and sought new accounts through sales.
- Analyzed financial statements and cash flow forecasts to inform operational strategy and decision-making.
- Met budget target through revenue and profit generation.

SALES & REPORTING ANALYST — Nigerian Bottling Company (Coca-Cola)

July 2017 - October 2017

- Assessed the processes related to the reporting area, seeking opportunities to improve and drive data quality
- Reported sales using data to provide insights that support the decision-making and strategic planning of NBC's Sales Team.
- Collated weekend & public holiday credit artifacts on behalf of the region for finance to apply to customer accounts.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to deliver mission-critical time-bound reports accurately.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN DATA SCIENCE

September 2022 - September 2023

- Manchester Metropolitan University, Manchester, United Kingdom

Key Modules: Principles of Data Science, Machine Learning Concepts, Computational Math Analysis and Statistics, Advanced Machine Learning, Data Management and Governance, Deep Learning, Algorithms & Data Structures, Big Data.

- Strong Knowledge and skills to acquire, curate, manage, and analyze data for solving real-world problems.
- Transferable computational and statistical thinking skills to create and deploy data-driven products.
- Able to communicate findings and address any legal or ethical questions that come with data processing.

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INDUSTRIAL CHEMISTRY

October 2014-November 2018

- Oduduwa University, Osun Nigeria.
 - Strong foundation in problem-solving and critical thinking skills.
 - Developed effective communication skills for presenting technical information to diverse audiences.

CERTIFICATIONS

•	Databricks Certified Machine Learning Associate	Ongoing
•	Microsoft Azure Al Fundamentals.	Ongoing
•	Data Camp Associate Data Scientist	Ongoing
•	Datacamp Data Scientist with R track.	Aug 2022
•	Google Data Analytics Certification.	June 2020
•	Microsoft Professional Program in Data Science.	Dec 2022
•	Google Data Analytics Certification.	June 2020
•	Google Skills for Africa; Digital Marketing Course, Customer Relationship Management	April 2020